Armando Diaz

Front End Developer

Profile

Front End Developer with 7 months of experience. I have completed various personal and academic projects that demonstrate my ability to create responsive, dynamic and accessible websites and web applications, following industry best practices and standards.

Experience

Inversiones La estrella Trayvale | Full Stack Developer

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

Responsibilities

- In charge of the design and programming of the application that allows the management of products, sales, payments and analytics, to go from the physical registration format to the digital one.
- Creation of UI components using React and UI material.
- Design of the database service with UML, authentication and operations with the Firebase APIs.

Portfolio | Free Game App | Front End Developer

MAY 2023 - JUNE 2023

Responsibilities

- Creation of the design for mobile and desktop devices.
- Consumes from third-party APIs.
- Layout and structure of the application.
- Optimization and performance.
- Deploy the application.

Technologies and skills

- React.js
- Next.js
- MongoDB
- Node.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Sass
- HTML
- CSS

- Front End Development
- Fast learning
- Responsive Design
- Collaboration
- User experience
- User interface design
- Problem resolution
- Use of agile methodology

Certifications

Front End Development Libraries | freeCodeCamp | Show

JULY 2022

Skills achieved

- Creating user interfaces using React components.
- Stylized interface with Bootstrap.
- Programming with Jquery
- Stylized interface with Sass.

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures | freeCodeCamp | Show **JULIO 2022**

- Skills achieved
 - Programming with JavaScript.
 - Implementation of algorithms and data structure.
 - Object Oriented Programming (OOP).
 - Functional Programming (FP).
 - Regular expressions

Responsive Web Design | freeCodeCamp | Show

MARZO 2022

Skills achieved

- Website layout with HTML.
- Styling with CSS.
- Creation and implementation of responsive designs.
- First Mobile Design Strategy.

Education

Computer engineer | Universidad Nacional Experimental de Guayana

OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT

Skills achieved

- Sorting and search algorithms.
- Programming in Python.
- Programming in C++
- C programming.

Idiomas

Spanish | Native

English| Technical